stanford.edu 2019-12-30

# Online Privacy Policy – Stanford University

Stanford University provides the following information relating to your privacy when using websites in the Stanford.EDU domain. This privacy policy covers all Stanford.EDU websites unless otherwise indicated on a specific website.

## Online Privacy Notice

This Online Privacy Notice applies to the information that we collect when you visit Stanford University’s main website ([www.stanford.edu](https://www.stanford.edu/)) and other websites that we own or control and link or refer to this Privacy Notice (together, the “ **Sites** ”). This Notice describes how this information is processed, as well as the choices that are available to you regarding the use of the information you provide.

Unless otherwise indicated on a specific Site, Stanford University (“ **Stanford** ”) is the data controller for all information collected under this Notice. Contact information for Stanford is listed at the end of this Notice.

This Notice does not apply to information collected from or about current or former employees, contractors, volunteers, post-doctorate fellows, and other workers of Stanford University (“ **Workers** ”) as part of their employment or working relationship with Stanford.

### Personal Information we collect and process:

When you access or use the Sites, we may collect and process the following types of information from you:

“ **Personal Information** ” is any information that we can reasonably use to identify you. If you are located in the European Economic Area (EEA), Personal Information includes all Personal Data as defined under EEA laws.

“ **Sensitive Personal Information** ” includes special categories of Personal Information (e.g., racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, genetic data, biometric data, data concerning health, and data concerning a natural person’s sex life or sexual orientation) for which applicable law provides enhanced protections.

The table below describes the Personal Information and Sensitive Personal Information that we collect, why we collect it, and our legal basis for processing it.

## Cookie Policy

This Cookie Policy applies to the cookies we use when you visit Stanford University’s main website (stanfordhs17.wpengine.com) and other websites that we own or control and link or refer to this Cookie Policy (together, the “Sites”).

This cookie policy provides you with more information about cookies, what types of cookies we use and how we use them. Our Sites use cookies with the intention of providing you with a user experience that best suits your needs, while concurrently allowing us to improve the design and functionality of our Sites. Cookies can be adjusted or disabled, and this policy provides you with instructions to do so.

### Cookies

A cookie is a file designed to contain a small amount of user and website information stored on a user’s computer. The file interacts with the user and the website to provide a webpage tailored to the user through its awareness of information held within the file. Cookies also have the ability to carry all or parts of the information stored within the file to other websites that the user may visit or to third parties.

#### Types of Cookies

A third-party cookie is placed by a domain other than that of the website the user is visiting.

A session cookie is temporary, linking the actions of a user during the any given browser session. When the browser is closed, the cookie is deleted.

A permanent cookie, also known as a persistent cookie, is stored for a specific period of time and activates each time the user visits the website that created the cookie.

### Our Use of Cookies

We use third-party, session and persistent cookies and similar technology to collect aggregate (non-personal) information about Sites usage by all of our visitors and to help us remember you and your preferences when you revisit the Sites. These cookies may stay on your browser into the future until they expire or you delete them. We also use technology to remember you the next time you log in. Some of these cookies are erased when you close your browser window and some persist for a period of time. Further general information about cookies and how they work is available at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

We may allow selected third parties to place cookies through the Sites to provide us with better insights into the use of the Sites or user demographics or to provide relevant advertising to you. These third parties may collect information about a user’s online activities over time and across different websites when he or she uses our Sites.

The cookies used on our Sites may include, but are not limited to, the following:

### Adjusting Cookie Settings

You can change your cookie settings by reviewing your internet browser’s cookie options. The links below to popular browsers may help you understand your cookie options better. Typically, such information can be found under the browser’s ‘Help’, ‘Preferences’ or ‘Options’ menus.

### Interest-Based Advertisements

Some of our Sites engage in online interest-based advertising to enhance your experience and show you advertisements that might interest you. Like many organizations, we and our advertising partners display tailored interest-based advertising using information you make available to us when you interact with our Sites.  Interest-based ads, also sometimes referred to as personalized or targeted ads, are displayed to you based on information from activities such as searching on our Sites or visiting websites that contain our content or ads. We do this using a variety of digital marketing networks and ad exchanges, and we use a range of advertising technologies like web beacons, pixels, ad tags, cookies, and mobile identifiers.

To learn more about interest-based ads or to opt-out of receiving third-party interest based ads, please visit [http://optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/) or [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note that if you opt out of interest-based advertising, you will still see advertisements – they will just not be tailored to your interests.  Also note that deleting browser cookies can remove the cookie preferences you have made, so you may need to opt-out again in the future.

### Blocking Cookies

Should you choose to decline or block cookies by adjusting your browser settings, including cookies essential to the Sites.  Please note that all or parts of our Sites may not be functional or accessible to you. Our Sites will issue cookies as soon you visit the Sites, unless your browser cookie settings are adjusted to prevent such an occurrence. Please review the information provided in this cookie policy on adjusting cookie settings for the browser of your choice.

## Sharing your Personal Information

We share your information internally at Stanford to facilitate and manage the purposes listed above. This includes third parties whom Stanford engages to process your Personal Information on our behalf for the purposes stated above, such as vendors who help Stanford with our marketing, application processing, and web hosting. Stanford may also share your personal data with government and law enforcement agencies or regulators to 1) comply with a legal process, subpoena, order or other legal or regulatory requirement applicable to us; 2) enforce our terms of use or other policies; or 3) pursue available legal remedies or defend against legal claims. Other third parties as you may so request as permitted by this and other Stanford University policies and applicable laws and regulations. Stanford University will not sell any personal information to third parties for their use in direct marketing, advertising, or promotion of their products or services.

## International Transfer of Personal Information

Personal information provided to us by users outside of the United States may be transferred to other countries such as the United States, where data protection laws may differ from those of your home country. By providing us with your information you acknowledge that your information will be transferred to the U.S. and processed on servers in the U.S. However, all reasonable steps will be taken to protect your privacy in accordance with the applicable data protection laws.

## Non-personally identifiable information we collect and process

Standard, non-personally identifiable internet log information such as browser type and navigation to various parts of the Sites, in an aggregated form, is collected for analytical purposes to improve the browsing experience of our Sites, update relevant content and improve the overall design.

## Information security

Stanford University takes the security of your personal information seriously. Our minimum security standards can be found at: <https://uit.stanford.edu/guide/securitystandards>.

## Marketing

Personal Information you submit through our Sites, such as your name, address and other contact information, may be collected by Stanford University for internal marketing and development purposes as well as to respond to your inquiry, complete a transaction for you, or fulfill other forms of customer service. You can choose not to receive marketing from us by “unsubscribing” using the instructions in any marketing email you receive from us.

## EEA Data Subject Rights

If you are an individual located in the EEA only, you will have the following rights with regard to your Personal Data:

  1. _Right of access_ You may request details of your Personal Information that we hold. We will confirm whether we are processing your Personal Information and we will disclose supplementary information including the categories of Personal Information, the sources from which it originated, the purpose and legal basis for the processing, the expected retention period, and the safeguards regarding Personal Information transfers to non-EEA countries, subject to the limitations set out in applicable statutes, regulations and other laws.
  2. _Right of correction_ We will comply with your request to edit and update incorrect Personal Information promptly.
  3. _Right to be forgotten_ At your request, we will delete your Personal Information promptly if: 
    * it is no longer necessary to retain your Personal Information;
    * you withdraw the consent which formed the basis of your Personal Information processing;
    * you object to the processing of your Personal Information and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for such processing;
    * the Personal Information was processed illegally; or
    * the Personal Information must be deleted for us to comply with our legal obligations.

We will inform any third parties we might have shared your Personal Information with of your deletion request.

We will decline your request for deletion if processing of your Personal Information is necessary:

    * to comply with our legal obligations;
    * in pursuit of a legal action;
    * to detect and monitor fraud; or
    * for the performance of a task in the public interest.
  4. _Right to restrict processing of your Personal Information_ At your request, we will limit the processing of your Personal Information if: 
    * you dispute the accuracy of your Personal Information;
    * your Personal Information was processed unlawfully and you request a limitation on processing, rather than the deletion of your Personal Information;
    * we no longer need to process your Personal Information, but you require your Personal Information in connection with a legal claim; or
    * you object to the processing pending verification as to whether an overriding legitimate ground for such processing exists.
  5. _Right to notice related to correction, deletion, and limitation on processing_ In so far as it is practicable, we will notify you of any correction, deletion, and/or limitation on processing of your Personal Information.
  6. _Right to data portability_ At your request, we will provide you free of charge with your Personal Information in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format, if: (i) you provided us with Personal Information; (ii) the processing of your Personal Information is based on your consent or required for the performance of a contract; or (iii) the processing is carried out by automated means.
  7. _Right to object_ Where we process your Personal Information based upon our legitimate interest then you have the right to object to this processing.
  8. _Right not to be subject to decisions based solely on automated processing_ You will not be subject to decisions with a legal or similarly significant effect (including profiling) that are based solely on the automated processing of your Personal Information, unless you have given us your explicit consent or where they are necessary for a contract with us.
  9. _Right to withdraw consent_ You have the right to withdraw any consent you may have previously given us at any time. If you withdraw your consent, this will not affect the lawfulness of our collecting, using and sharing of your Personal Information up to the point in time that you withdraw your consent. Even if you withdraw your consent, we may still use your information that has been fully anonymized and does not personally identify you.
  10. _Right to complain to a supervisory authority_ If you are not satisfied with our response, you have the right to complain to or seek advice from a supervisory authority and/or bring a claim against us in any court of competent jurisdiction.

If you wish to contact us in connection with the exercise of your rights listed above, please email us at privacy@stanford.edu.  We will respond to your written request without unreasonable delay and in accordance with any deadlines imposed by law. Unless we notify you at the time of your request, we will not charge you any fee in connection with the exercise of your rights.

## Access and Choice

Stanford students can manage privacy settings for their directory information in [Axess](https://axess.sahr.stanford.edu/). Faculty, staff and other Stanford affiliates can manage their privacy settings in [StanfordYou](https://stanfordyou.stanford.edu/).

You can choose not to receive emails from us by “unsubscribing” using the instructions in any email you receive from us. This will not stop us from sending emails about your account or your transactions with us.

## Document Retention

We keep your Personal Information for as long as needed to fulfill the particular purpose for which it was collected. We may also retain your records if legally required or to fulfill a legitimate interest.

## Updates to Privacy Policy

Stanford reserves the right to modify this Privacy Notice at any time. Prior to changes to the Privacy Notice, we will provide you notice, which shall be available at privacy.stanford.edu, prior to the effective date of any notice. Your continued use of the Sites after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

## Contact Information

For more information on how we collect and process your Personal Information, or if you have any complaints please contact [privacy@stanford.edu](mailto:privacy@stanford.edu).

## Effective Date

The effective date of this policy is May 25, 2018.
